让我们详细谈谈其中一些monadic函数。
Let’s talk in detail about some of these monadic functions.
首先，改变像素类型-经常用于转换无符号整数
First, changing the pixel type—quite useful frequently to convert an unsigned integer
图像成双重图像。所以我们要做的是获取范围内的输入像素
image into a double image. So what we are going to do is take input pixels in the range
0到255，这些是整数，所以他们有0,1,2,3等值，我们
0 through 255, and these are integers so they have got value 0, 1, 2, 3 and so on, and we
将它们映射到0到1之间的实数范围。我们可以表示
are going to map them into the range of real numbers between 0 and 1. And we can represent
通过图形进行映射，如右图所示。
that mapping by a graph, which is shown there on the right.
相反，我们可以将双精度图像转换为uint8图像。所以我们想要什么
Conversely, we can convert double precision images into uint8 images. So what we want
现在要做的是取0到1范围内的像素，并将它们映射到整数值
to do now is to take pixels in the range 0 to 1 and map them into integer values, in
范围为0到255，我们再次可以用图形表示这种映射。请注意，两者都有
the range of 0 to 255, and again we can represent this mapping graphically. Note that in both
例如，映射是一条直线，它以1的渐变穿过原点。
cases, the mapping is a straight line and it passes through the origin with a gradient of 1.
我们也可以改变亮度
We could also change the brightness of the
图像，我们可以通过几种方式来做到这一点。一种方法是简单地添加一个
image and there are a couple of ways that we can do that. One way is simply to add a
场景中所有灰度值的常数正值。
constant positive value to all of the grey values within the scene.
所以f（x）是输入值x加上1/4的值。如果我们以图形方式表示
So f(x) is the input value x, plus the value of 1/4. And if we represent that graphically
我们在这里看到这种形状，会发生的是一些像素会超过
we see this shape here, and what happens is that some of the pixels are going to exceed
值1.因此我们应用我们称之为饱和度的东西：我们不允许它们更大
the value of 1. So we apply what we call a saturation: we don’t allow them to be greater
超过1，所以我们的产品线已经扭曲了。如果我们将这种转变应用于莫娜
than 1, so our line has got a kink in it. If we apply this transformation to the Mona
Lisa图像我们可以看到确实变得更亮的图像。
Lisa image we can see that indeed the image that has become brighter.
另一种增加图像亮度的方法，通常称为增加
Another way to increase the brightness of the image, often referred to actually as increasing
图像的对比度是将所有灰度值乘以常数，并且在
the contrast of the image, is to multiply all the grey values by a constant, and in
在这种情况下，我们将所有灰度值乘以2的值。我们可以看到
this case we are going to multiply all the grey values by the value of 2. We can see
如果我们再次以图形方式表示，那么线的斜率现在比它更陡峭
if we represent this graphically again, the slope of the line now is steeper than it was
之前。这条线现在有一个陡峭，梯度为2，饱和度问题
before. This line now has got a steepness, a gradient of, 2, and the saturation problem
现在更加明显。因此，如果我们申请，有很多价值观
is more pronounced now. So there are a lot of values which if we apply
x的函数的值大于1，我们不得不限制它们
the function to x would have a value much greater than 1, and we have had to limit those
或者将它们饱和到最大值1，这是我们在表示图像时所拥有的
or saturate those to the maximum value of 1, which we have when we represent images
双精度数。我们现在看到的图像，
in double precision numbers. What we can see now when we look at the image,
我们可以看到它确实更具对比度，
we can see that it is indeed much more contrasty,
但我们也可以看到像素已经饱和的一些区域。
but we can also see some areas where the pixels have become saturated.
像这样1-x这样的简单函数会产生一个
A simple function like this 1-x produces a
负面形象。所以这是图形化的：具有斜率的线
negative image. So this is it graphically: a line with a slope
-1。这里发生的是明亮的输入像素在输出图像中变暗
of -1. And what happens here are bright input pixels become dark in the output image and
反之亦然。我之前提到过这种称为分色的技术，你可以经常这样做
vice versa. I mentioned earlier the technique called posterization, which you can often
在流行艺术中找到。我们所做的是限制可能的输出亮度值
find in pop art. And what we do is we limit the number of possible output brightness values
那可以。如果您愿意，我们会对其进行量化，因此在此处显示的图像中我们允许
that there can be. We quantise it if you like, so in the image shown here what we have allowed
只有四个可能的输出灰度值，因此这个阶梯映射转换为连续的
are only four possible output grey values, so this staircase mapping converts a continuous
输入灰度级范围为四种可能输出值之一。
range of input grey levels to one of four possible output values.